parkinson.org 2019-11-20

# Parkinson’s Foundation: Better Lives. Together.

#### Privacy Policy

We at the Parkinson's Foundation are committed to respecting the privacy of our website visitors.  This page describes our privacy policy regarding the information we collect from you during your visit to our site, how we may use it, and how we will protect the information which you choose to provide us. Our privacy policy is reviewed against the Better Business Bureau Wise Giving Alliance's Standards for Charity Accountability.

### Personally Identifiable Information

The foundation does not require that you provide personally identifiable information in order to use our website.  Personally identifiable information includes your name, address, zip code and telephone number, e-mail address and any other information which might be used to identify you individually. You may provide personally identifiable information to us while using the site in three situations: (1) while making a donation, (2) when ordering from our online store, (3) while communicating with the foundation, and (4) while participating in our online forums.  Participating in online forums is addressed below.  If you decide to support the activities of the foundation by making a tax deductible contribution with a credit card, we will collect the information needed to complete the transaction. If you order materials from our online store, we will collect the information needed to complete the transaction. If you contact the foundation, we will collect the information necessary to respond to you and also will receive any information you disclose in your message.  When you are making a donation, ordering from our online store or contacting the foundation, we will clearly disclose how we intend to use the information you provide on the page in which it is collected.  In every case, we will take reasonable precautions to prevent your personal information from being intercepted by any third party using standard web techniques including encryption and firewalls to protect the data.  In these cases, when the foundation receives personally identifiable information, we may use it for reasonable purposes. For example, we may use this information to contact you to provide you with information we believe may be of interest. It may also be used for compiling data and analyses to understand and serve your needs.  Data is also compiled to evaluate how well we are doing at accomplishing our mission.

In contrast to the information that we collect in order deliver services, we also offer forums where site visitors can exchange ideas and discuss issues with healthcare providers and allied professionals.  If you provide personally identifiable information in one of our online forums, you do so **at your own risk**.  The foundation cannot be held responsible for personal information posted in the online forums.  There is a disclaimer on the forum page that also warns of this risk.

Personally identifiable information will never be sold, rented or exchanged outside of the foundation, its successors or assigns, and its vendors bound by non-disclosure agreements unless the user is first notified and expressly consents to such transfer.

### Use of Cookies

Like most websites, the foundation's website may store information on your computer in a small file called a "cookie."  These cookies never store personally identifiable information and do not compromise your privacy.  Cookies are used exclusively to improve the user experience by providing continuity in your browsing the site.  If you access the site via a public computer, be sure to click "log off" at the end of your session.  The site will warn you not to use the "remember me" functionality (enabled by cookies) if you are at a public computer.

#### Other Terms and Conditions

### Use of the Online Forum

The Parkinson's Foundation website includes several discussion forums ("forums"). By participating in the forums, users agree to send and receive messages that are both proper and related to the forum topic. The following actions represent examples of unacceptable practices, and may result in the foundation taking action against violators: defaming, harassing, threatening, or otherwise violating the legal rights of others, including their privacy; misrepresenting one's person, background, or character; posting any defamatory, infringing, obscene, false, or unlawful material; selling, advertising, or exchanging any goods or services unless expressly allowed; posting any copyrighted material owned by a third party.  This list is not exclusive and may be changed at any time with or without prior notice. The foundation may alter or remove any messages or postings to our site at its discretion, including those we deem inappropriate or offensive. You use the Parkinson's Foundation website at your own risk. Please do not post personally identifiable information in the forums.  If you do, the foundation cannot be held responsible for the use of that information. 

### Links To Other Sites

As a resource to our visitors the foundation may provide links to other websites and links to other sites may be posted in the forums. Links posted in the forums are generally not screened and any link posted in the forum is followed at your own risk.  For links posted outside the forum, we try to carefully choose websites which we believe are useful and meet our high standards for the accuracy and utility of information. However, because website design and content can change so quickly we cannot guarantee the standards of every website to which we link. Likewise, we are not responsible for the content of any non-Parkinson's Foundation site. We also cannot guarantee the privacy policies of these other sites and suggest you check the privacy policies of those sites directly.

### Non-Parkinson's Foundation Products and Resources

Any reference to a commercial or noncommercial product, process, service or company is not an endorsement or recommendation by the Parkinson's Foundation.

The Parkinson's Foundation does not endorse or recommend products, services or manufacturers. The Parkinson's Foundation assumes no liability whatsoever for the use or contents of any product or service mentioned.

### Communications from the Foundation

If you wish to stop receiving any e-mail or other communications from the foundation or if you have submitted personally identifiable information through a Parkinson's Foundation website and would like to have that information deleted, please notify us and it will be done promptly.  Click on the "contact us" link in the navigation bar to contact the foundation.

### Security

The Parkinson's Foundation takes data security seriously.  The foundation collects data that is covered by the medical privacy law HIPAA and is subjected to periodic audits by our banks.  Information collected by the foundation (besides that which you may submit in the forums) is stored behind a firewall and protected using secure encryption technologies.  While no security steps can offer 100 percent protection we utilize state-of-the-art, industry-standard protocols to prevent unauthorized access to the information we hold. We will limit access to personal information to those foundation personnel with a need to know it. We educate our staff about their duty to protect your privacy and provide training regarding the policy described herein.

### Logo Usage

Use of the Parkinson's Foundation registered trademarks (logos) without Foundation permission is prohibited. Please send written requests or questions to Leilani Pearl at [lpearl@parkinson.org](mailto:lpearl@parkinson.org).

### Return, Refund, and/or Cancellation Policy

In the event you wish a refund of your gift or cancellation of a recurring credit card payment, please call, email us at [contact@parkinson.org](mailto:contact@parkinson.org) or write to the attention of Donor Services, Parkinson’s Foundation, 200 SE 1st Street, Suite 800, Miami, FL 33131, including your name, address, details of the amount donated, date of the donation, the reason for the request and, if a credit card authorization is to be cancelled, the card number, expiration date and ccv number.

### Changes

The Parkinson's Foundation reserves the right to make changes to this policy without notice.  Any changes to this privacy policy will be reflected in changes on this page. Please check this privacy page periodically to review any changes that may have been made.

### Contact Us

If you have specific questions or concerns about the Foundation's privacy policy, please contact us at the following address:

200 SE 1st Street  
Suite 800  
Miami, Florida 33131  
Toll-free Helpline: 1-800-4PD-INFO (473-4636)  
Fax: (305) 537-9901  
E-mail inquiries: [contact@parkinson.org](mailto:contact@parkinson.org)
